(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
Doctor Who (1963) 10x03 Fontier in Space
(whopix fan edit version)
《神秘博士》老版第十季第三集 太空边境 (粉丝剪辑版)
【翻译】巴蛮子sz
【时间轴】巴蛮子sz
【校对】巴蛮子sz
(基于opensubtitles.org 英文字幕翻译)
（注意: 本字幕不针对原版视频，而是针对
Whopix 粉丝剪辑版本 http://wp.me/p1mHFo-xY ）
But all these charges are false, Your Highness.
这些指控都是假的，殿下
We are not attacking Draconian ships. We never have!
我们没有攻击龙族的船，从来没有
Our soldiers have seen the Earthmen attack us.
我们士兵倒看见过地球人攻击我们
Our cargos have been stolen.
我们的货物被偷走
We are Draconians, we do not lie.
我们是龙族人，我们不撒谎
The honour of your race is well known, Your Highness.
你们种族的名声是众所周知的，殿下
That is why I cannot understand your actions.
这也是为什么我弄不明白你们的行动
Actions?
行动?
You attack our ships, you steal their cargoes,
你们攻击我们的船，你们抢走他们的货物
you ignore our protests
and just meet them with these counter-charges.
你忽略我们的抗议，只是提出这些反诉
Our charges are true but yours are false.
我们的指控是真实的，但你们的是假的
We do not attack your ships.
我们不会攻击你们的船
Well, I'm never going in that thing again.
我可再也不进去那里了
Oh, come on, Jo, be reasonable.
哦，得了，Jo, 理性一点
Only you could manage to have a traffic accident in space.
只有你能在太空当中制造一场交通事故
- Well, we didn't hit it, did we?
- Didn't we? Where's this then?
- 不过，我们并没有撞上，对吧? - 没有? 那这里是哪里?
Well, by a rather brilliant last-minute course correction,
这个嘛，在最后紧急关头，凭着我漂亮的转弯
I've managed to materialise the TARDIS inside the spaceship.
我把 TARDIS 开到了这艘飞船的内部
But to avoid hitting it,
不过为了避免跟它相撞
I've had to make a random jump back into normal space.
我不得不跳回了普通空间
Terrific, but what do we do now?
挺棒，但我们现在做什么
Well, if I'm to get us back to Earth,
I'd better find out where we are.
唔，如果我要把我们带回地球，我最好要先搞清楚我们在哪里
I'll just go and check the instruments.
我去检查一下仪器
HARDY: You won't believe this.
你不会相信的
- Now what? - Maybe it's a wreck.
- 现在怎么办? - 可能是艘废船
Try and make contact. They may need help.
试着联系一下，他们可能需要帮助
This is Earth cargo ship C982 in close proximity to you.
我们是地球货船C982，就在你们旁边
Do you read me? Do you read me?
你们能听到吗? 你们能听到吗?
(WHITE NOISE OVER RADIO)
- Try again. - Do you read me?
- 再试试  - 你们能听到吗?
Are you in need of assistance?
你们是否需要协助?
(WHITE NOISE OVER RADIO)
It's a weird-looking crate.
这箱子看起来真奇怪
(HIGH PITCHED BLEEPING)
Draconians!
龙族人!
- Doctor? - Well, I think I know where we are.
- 博士? - 我想我知道我们在哪儿了
I've got a pretty good idea about when.
而且对于我们在何时也基本清楚了
- Come and take a look at this.
- A look at what?
- 过来看一下这个 - 看看什么?
That.
那个
Well, it's just a spaceship, Jo.
只是一艘飞船，Jo
Now, I reckon we must be somewhere in the 26th century.
现在我估计我们肯定在26世纪的某处
Well, interstellar travel's pretty routine by now.
在这个时代，星际旅行已经比较普遍了
A moment ago, it seemed to change shape.
就此刚才，它好像在变形
- Hmm? - It was when I heard that noise.
- 嗯? - 就是那时我听到那个声音的
Didn't you hear it?
你没有听到吗?
Well, I did hear something but very faintly.
我也听到点声音，但比较微弱
Come on, Jo. Let's go and find the crew.
这儿来，Jo. 我们去找找船员
I want to find the exact date for my calculations.
我想去问问具体的日子，看看我的计算对不对
- HARDY: They're going to attack us!
- STEWART: Get the blasters.
- 他们要攻击我们 - 去拿枪
HARDY: You can't take on a battle cruiser!
你没法打赢一艘战斗巡航舰
Get the blasters!
去拿枪!
Emergency, emergency, red alert.
紧急情况，紧急情况，红色警报
This is Earth cargo ship C982
这里是地球货船C982
on coordinate 8972/6483.
目前在坐标8972/6483
We are under attack by
a Draconian battle cruiser, galaxy class,
我们正被一艘龙族战斗巡航舰攻击，星系级
equipped with neutronic missiles.
装备有中子导弹
Emergency, emergency!
紧急情况，紧急情况
Oh, how do you do?
I'm sorry about this intrusion.
哦，你好，很抱歉这样闯进来
HARDY: Who are you?
你是谁!
(HIGH-PITCHED BLEEPING)
DOCTOR: I said how do you do?
HARDY: Dragons!
- 我说了你好 - 龙!
- Drop that gun. - Gun?
- 把枪扔掉 - 枪?
I haven't got a gun. This is simply my hand.
我没有枪，这只是我的手
(GASPING) No!
不!
-DOCTOR: Jo, what's the matter with you?
- He's a Drashig!
- Jo, 你怎么了? - 这是个 Drashig!
DOCTOR: Nonsense, it's simply a man with a gun.
Now pull yourself together.
别胡说，只是一个普通人拿了一把枪. 冷静一点
(注: Jo 所看见的怪物名叫 Drashig ，这是在上一个故事
Carnival of Monsters 出现过的一种猎食怪物)
This is Earth cargo ship C982.
这里是地球货船C982
Situation, red alert.
状态，红色警报
Draconian battle cruiser about to lock on now.
龙族战斗巡航舰即将对接上我们的船
All anti-boarding procedures carried out.
所有反登船措施已经实施
Awaiting instructions. Out.
等待指示. 完毕
This is the commander of the Draconian battle cruiser.
我是龙族战斗巡航舰的指挥官
We are locked onto your vessel
我们已经对接上你们的船只
and are about to board.
即将登船
If you offer any resistance,
如果你们进行任何抵抗
you will be destroyed.
你们将会被消灭
Open the hatch of your airlock.
打开你们减压舱的舱门
I found these two Dragons in the hold.
我在货舱里找到了这两条龙
But that's impossible. They...
They're only just locking on.
这不可能啊，他们才刚刚对接上
Doctor, what's happening? What's going on?
博士，发生了什么? 什么情况?
I'm not sure, Jo. Something rather intriguing.
我不确定，Jo. 有点奇怪
If you resist, we can destroy you
with our neutronic weapons.
如果你们反抗，我们能用我们的中子武器消灭你们
If you destroy our ship, you won't get the cargo.
如果你摧毁我们的飞船，你就得不到货物了
Oh, so that's what it's all about.
哦，原来是为了这个
Open the hatch to your airlock
打开你们减压舱的舱门
or we shall enter your ship by force.
否则我们要采用武力进入了
- We refuse. - They can blow us to pieces!
- 我们拒绝执行 - 他们会把我们轰成碎片的
I've sent a message to Earth asking for help.
我已经给地球发信息求救了
This is a transcript of a distress call
from one of our ships.
这是有记录，抄录自我们一艘船说发出的求救信号
"From Earth's cargo ship number C982
on coordinate 8972/6483.
"来自地球货船，编号C982，坐标 8972/6483
"We are under attack by a Draconian battle cruiser,
"我们正被一艘龙族战斗巡航舰攻击
"galaxy class, equipped with neutronic missiles."
"星系级，配备有中子导弹"
The treaty between our two empires
established a frontier in space.
我们两个帝国通过协商建立了一个太空边界
We have never violated that frontier.
我们来从来没有违反过这个条约
You have invaded our part of the galaxy many times.
但你们已经数次入侵我们星系
In pursuit of your ships when they have raided ours!
那也是因为你们的飞船先攻击了我们，我们追他们才越过边界的
We've been very patient, perhaps too patient.
我们一直很有耐性，也许是太有耐性了
General Williams!
威廉将军!
I take it a rescue attempt has been mounted?
我认为已经在安排营救了吧?
We've established an automatic procedure,
我们已经一套自动化过程
because of the frequency of these attacks.
因为这种攻击已经变得很频繁了
Then I suggest you go and supervise the matter.
那我建议你离开，去监控好营救过程
There's no need.
这并没有必要
Please do as I say.
请按我说的做
As you wish, Madam President.
听您的吩咐，总统夫人
Your general is insolent.
你的将军太无礼了
We know the hatred he has always felt for our people.
我们都知道他一直都对我们种族怀着仇恨
Long ago he caused war.
很久以前他挑起了战争
Now he wishes to do so again.
现在他还打算再来一次
He's a soldier, Your Highness, and he's angry.
他是个战士，殿下，而且他很愤怒
The people of Earth are angry.
地球人都很愤怒
So are the nobles of my father's court!
我父亲的王廷上那些贵族也一样!
I must ask you to take my personal appeal
to your father, the Emperor.
我必须得让你把我个人的呼吁带给你父皇
He must put a stop to these attacks.
他必须叫停这些攻击
If Draconia has some grievances against Earth,
如果龙族对地球有什么不满
then this is not the way to deal with them.
这也并不是处理问题的正确做法
Many of our noblemen felt it was a mistake
to make a treaty with the Earthmen.
我们贵族中的许多人认为跟地球人缔结条约是一个错误
Perhaps they were right.
也许他们是对的
You attack our ships and when we protest
你们攻击了我们的飞船，当我们提出抗议的时候
you trick us with lies and evasions.
你们又用谎言和否认来欺骗我们
I give you a final warning.
我给你们最后的警告
The path you are treading leads only to war.
你们走的这条路只会通向战争
And in that war, Draconia will destroy you!
而在这场战争里，龙族人会摧毁你们
(HISSING)
They'll be through that door any minute!
他们马上就能穿过那个门了
Doctor, what are you doing?
博士，你在做什么?
I'm reversing the polarity of my ultrasonic screwdriver's power source,
我在把音速起子上电源的极性翻转过来
thereby converting it into an extremely powerful electromagnet.
这样它就变成了一个极强的电磁铁
Oh. What good will that do?
哦，那又有什么用呢?
You wait and see, Jo.
你等着看吧，Jo
Is it working?
这能行吗?
(LOCK GRATING)
Yes, I think so.
是的，我觉得可以
- I'm going to get the prisoners. - What for?
- 我去把囚犯带出来 - 带出来做什么?
We're using them as hostages, remember?
我们可以用他们作为人质，记得吧?
You'd better be quick about it. We haven't got much time.
你最好动作快点，我们没有太多时间
- How is it going? - Nearly there.
- 进展怎么样 - 快好了
(LOCK GRATING)
There you are, that's it.
搞定了，就是这样
Oh, how very embarrassing.  Good afternoon.
哦，好尴尬啊. 下午好
- Out. - That's just where we were going.
- 出来 - 我们正打算出来呢
We're going to meet your friends.
我们去见见你们的朋友
- Come on! Get up there! - Come on, they're almost through.
- 快点，上这里来! - 快点，他们快打穿了
HARDY: Get in front! If your friends start shooting,
they'll get you first.
站前面去! 如果你的朋友们开始开枪，先射死的是你们
- But they're not our friends! - You are part of their boarding party.
- 但他们不是我们的朋友! - 你们俩是他们登船小队的成员
They haven't boarded yet. They're still breaking through that door.
他们还没有登船. 他们还在切割舱门呢
- Now, try and be logical, man. - They're coming through!
- 能不能讲点理，伙计 - 他们过来了
- Ogrons! - DOCTOR: Back to the TARDIS, Jo. Back!
- Ogrons!  - 快回到 TARDIS, Jo. 回去!
Doctor! Doctor!
博士，博士!
JO: (SOFTLY) Doctor?
博士?
- Jo? - JO: Doctor!
- Jo? - 博士?
- Jo? - JO: Doctor, I'm over here.
- Jo? - 博士，我在这里
All right, Jo, what are you doing in there?
好，Jo, 你在那里面干什么
Oh, Doctor, thank goodness, you're all right.
哦，博士，感谢神灵，你没事
I thought they'd killed you.
我以为他们杀了你
Come on, come and sit down.
来吧，过来坐下
Must have been some kind of neuronic stun gun.
肯定是某种中子击晕枪
I wonder why they didn't kill me? What exactly happened, Jo?
很奇怪他们为什么没杀了我? 到底发生了什么，Jo?
Well, they took the cargo, threw me in here and...
呃..他们把货拿走了，然后把我扔到这里面就...
- Doctor? - Hmm?
- 博士 - 唔?
- They also took the TARDIS. - Oh...
- 他们还带走了 TARDIS - 噢...
Oh, we're stranded. What are we going to do?
哦，我们陷入困境了. 现在怎么办?
Well, try and get the TARDIS back, of course.
当然是想办法把 TARDIS 弄回来
(JO SIGHS)
Why should the Ogrons attack this ship?
为什么 Ogrons 要攻击这艘船?
- To steal the cargo. - No. No, there's more to it than that.
- 为了偷货呗 - 不，不，远不仅于此
That... That sound that you heard,
那个...你听到的那个声音
it's all too sophisticated for the Ogrons.
对于 Ogrons 来说过于复杂了
- Well, they're gone now. - Yeah, the question is, where?
- 他们现在已经走了 - 对，但问题是，去了哪儿?
Hey, Doctor, last time we met the Ogrons
嘿，博士，上一次我们碰到 Ogrons 的时候
they were working for the Daleks, right?
他们在为 Daleks 卖命，对不?
- Well, you don't suppose that that... - No, no, not necessarily.
- 这，你不是想说... - 不，不，不一定
No, the Ogrons are mercenaries.
不，这些 Ogrons 都是雇佣兵
Other life forms use them to do their dirty work.
其他的种族会用他们来干些脏活
Come on, Jo, let's go and find the crew.
来吧，Jo, 我们去看看能不能找到船员
(博士与 Jo 上一次碰到 Ogrons 是在09x01 The Day of the Daleks 这集,
所以这次 Ogrons 这次一露面，Jo 就能认出他们了)
Take a look at that one.
你看一下那个
DOCTOR: It's all right, Jo. We're being rescued.
没事了，Jo. 我们得救了
- What happened? - Well, don't worry, old chap.
- 发生了什么? - 别担心，老伙计
You'll be all right now. I think...
你很快就没事了，我想...
Draconians! They're boarding!
龙族人! 他们要上船了!
- Stewart? Who are you? - Passengers.
- Stewart? 你们是谁?  - 乘客
I see. Having a fancy dress party? What happened?
我明白了，在开化妆舞会? 刚才什么情况?
- Dragons attacked us. - Did they get the cargo?
- 那些龙袭击了我们 - 他们劫走货物了没
- I don't know. - Yes, they took everything.
- 我不清楚 - 是的，他们全拿走了
Including some rather valuable property of mine.
包括我个人的一些相当值钱的东西
- Well, tough luck. - Oh, thank you very much.
- 这样啊，挺倒霉啊 - 哦，很感谢你们
- Dragons... They attacked us. - Yes, we know.
- 那些龙...他们攻击了我们 - 是的，我们知道了
You say you're passengers.
Isn't that a little unusual on a cargo ship?
你说你们是乘客，这对于一艘货船来讲是不是有点不合常理啊?
Well, we're here, aren't we?
但是，我们现在就在这里，对不?
Where did you pick these two up?
你们在哪里捎带上他们俩的?
I don't know. I can't seem to remember...
我不知道，好像想不起来了...
Pull yourself together! How did they get on board?
站好了! 他们是怎么上船的?
Stowaways... That's it, they were stowaways.
偷渡的... 对了，他们是偷渡的
- They were sending messages. - That's right.
- 他们曾经往外发送信息 - 那就对了
They were helping the Dragons. They're traitors!
他们在帮助那些龙，他们是叛徒!
But that's absolute nonsense.
这绝对是胡说
Look, we didn't want to be on this ship. It was an accident.
是这样，我们并不想到这艘船上来的，是一次事故
You said you were passengers.
你刚说你们是乘客
I was merely trying to avoid a lot of tiresome explanations, old chap.
我只是想把事情弄简单一点，免得浪费半天口舌，老伙计
Stewart, I'll leave Kemp on board to take your ship back to Earth.
Stewart, 我把 Kemp 留在船上，带你们回地球
What about these two?
这两个人怎么办?
Lock them in the hold, put a guard on them.
把他们所进置留室，派人看着他们
- But we haven't done anything. - They say you have. Take them away.
- 但我们没干过任何事啊 - 他们说你干过. 带走
Now, if you'll only listen to me...
诶，如果你能听我说...
You can talk to Earth Security.
你跟地球安全部去说吧
They'll listen, it's their business.
他们会听的，这是他们的工作
- Put them in the starboard cubicle. - All right, get moving.
- 把他们带到右舷小隔间去 - 好的，走
In there.
进去
Oops. No need to push.
噢，没必要推啊
Doctor, well, now the Ogrons have gone,
博士，对了，既然 Ograns 已经走了
why don't the crewmen remember what really happened?
为什么这些船员还是想不起来真正发生了什么?
Because the true facts have been erased from their minds, that's why.
因为真相已经从他们大脑里面抹掉了，这就是为什么
Well, yes, but why did they keep telling lies about us?
哦，这样，但为什么他们又一直说胡说八道呢?
Oh, they don't know that they're lying, Jo.
哦，他们并不知道他们在胡说八道，Jo
They're desperately trying to fit us into their version of things.
他们只是在尽力地把我们装进他们那个版本的真实中去
Well, what are we going to do then?
那，我们该怎么办?
Well, when we get back to Earth,
现在，等我们回到地球
we've got to reach someone in authority
whose mind isn't already closed.
我们应该能碰到某个当权者，他的大脑没有那么封闭?
Closed to what?
封闭?
Jo, look, these people believe
Jo, 你看，这些人相信
that the Draconians are attacking their spaceships, right?
是龙族人袭击了他们的飞船，对吧?
- Right. - We know that they're wrong, don't we?
- 是的   - 我们知道他们说的是错的，是不?
Well, yes, it was Ogrons.
嗯，是的，是 Ogrons 干的
Oh, we also know that the Ogrons couldn't possibly
我们也知道 Ogrons 不太可能
have created that hallucinatory device
能制造出那种致幻设备
that makes the Earthmen think they're Draconians.
可以让地球人产生错觉，以为是龙族人袭击了他们
Oh. Oh, well, that's simple then.
哦，哦，这样就简单了
I mean, what we've got to is find out what's going on,
我是说，我们要做的，就是搞明白到底是怎么一回事
who's behind the Ogrons, where they've taken the TARDIS,
谁在操纵这些 Ogrons, 他们又把 TARDIS 带到哪里去了
go and get it back and then we can all go home.
我们去把它找回来，然后我们就可以回家了
- Right? - Right.
- 对吧?  - 对
Oh. I don't know what I've been worrying about.
哦，我不知道一直在担心什么
We are now in space port 10.
我们正在十号太空站
The ship will land in 15 minutes. The crew are safe.
飞船将在15分钟内降落，船员都安全
Also aboard, two human stowaways, origins unknown.
船上还有两个偷渡的人类，来源未知
I want a cordon around the landing area,
the minute that ship touches down.
我需要飞船一着地，就在周边拉起警戒线
Nobody on, nobody off till I get there.
在我到达之前，任何人不得进入，任何人不得离开
Sir.
先生
I'd better get down there.
I want handle the preliminary interrogations myself.
我最好还是下去，我想亲自进行初步的审讯
- Outside. - We want to see somebody in authority.
- 出来 - 我们要见你们老大
You're going to, but outside.
你会见到的，不过得先出来
Now then, what's all this about?
既然这样，这些又什么意思
- Draconian agents? Are you sure? - What else can they be?
- 龙族特工? 你确定吗?   - 要不然还能是什么
Their story is obvious nonsense.
他们的故事显然说不通啊
But why? We...
为什么? 我们...
Why would the Draconians leave them on board the ship?
为什么龙族人会把他们继续留在飞船上?
The Draconians are preparing for war.
那些龙族人正在准备一场战争
You're still only suspecting that. There is no proof.
你这只是在怀疑，但没有证据
Then they need to plant human agents,
所以他们需要安插两名人类特工
traitors, on this planet to sabotage our war effort.
两个叛徒，好让他们在这个星球上破坏我们的反击
But we are bound to suspect them. They must have realised.
但我们肯定会怀疑他们啊，他们肯定能想到这个
The Draconians probably thought the crew was dead.
那些龙族人也许认为船员都死了
We could easily have accepted those two as passengers,
以为我们会轻易地相信这两个家伙真的是乘客
two unfortunate refugees from a Draconian attack,
是两个躲避龙族人袭击的不幸难民
- When did you last eat? - Quite some while ago.
- 你上次什么时候吃饭的? - 有些时候了
Well, I'll see they send you some food.
好吧，我去让他们给你们送点食物进来
I'd like to get a message through to your president.
我期望给你们的总统带个信息
Not a chance.
别妄想了
I'm going straight back to my ship.
我就直接回我的船了
Don't want to get mixed up with security.
别想着破坏这里的安保设施
It's not healthy.
这对你不好
- Look, I'll give you a piece of advice. - DOCTOR: Yes?
- 对了，我要给你们一个小建议 - 什么...
Sooner or later, you're going to tell them everything.
或早或迟，你们都给告诉他们全部实情
They'll use the mind probe. You talk to them now.
他们会使用思维探测器的，你们还是现在就说实话吧
You'll save yourselves a lot of trouble.
这也可以给你们自己省去很多麻烦
PRESIDENT: And you are quite sure it was a Draconian battle cruiser.
你确定那是一艘龙族战斗巡航舰吗?
Of course, Madam.
当然，夫人
They locked on and boarded us.
他们锁定了我们，强行登了船
We saw them. They were Draconians.
我们都看见了，他们是龙族人
Thank you. That will be all.
谢谢你，你们可以走了
I hope you will soon recover from your ordeal.
期望你很快从这些磨难中恢复过来
Well, Your Highness?
怎样，殿下?
These men are your servants.
他们都是你的人
They are saying what they have been ordered to say.
你们让他们说什么，他们就说什么
On this occasion, we have more than our servants to confront you with.
这次不同了，能跟你对质的不仅仅是我们的人
We have captured two of your human agents.
我们抓住了你的两个人类间谍
We have no human agents.
我们没有人类间谍
Subversion and espionage are expressly forbidden
破坏与间谍活动是明令禁止的
by the treaty of peace between our two empires.
我们两国的和平条约已经写得很清楚了
A treaty which you have flagrantly broken.
这个条约已经被你们戳得千疮百孔了
I shall return to my embassy.
我回大使馆了
Just a moment please, Your Highness. Bring them in.
请等一下，殿下. 把他们带进来
These people stowed away on the cargo ship.
这两个人偷渡在那艘货船上
They transmitted signals
他们往外面发信号
which enabled your battle cruiser to home in on its prey.
引导你们的战斗巡航舰过来实施攻击
I know nothing of this.
我对此毫不知情
Perhaps you do not, but some servant of the Draconian empire employed them.
也许你是不知道，但龙族帝国的某些人雇佣了他们
Madam, I can assure that I've never been employed by anybody.
夫人，我可以保证，我从来没有被任何人雇佣
Least of all by the Draconians.
更别说被龙族人雇佣了
Your servants should have been better rehearsed in their lies.
你的喽罗应该好好排练一下如何撒谎
Or they're showing a misguided loyalty
to their Draconian masters.
或许他们只是对龙族主人展现了错误的忠诚
If we really were working for the Draconians,
如果我们真的是在为龙族人办事
why did they leave us in your ship?
他们怎么会把我们留在你们的船上
To act as spies when you were brought back to Earth.
为了方便你们被带回地球之后可以继续充当间谍
Allow me to congratulate you, sir.
请允许我祝贺你，先生
You have the most totally closed mind that I've ever encountered.
你拥有我所见过的最封闭的头脑
Madam, I beg of you to listen to me.
夫人，我请求你能听我说
Some third party is trying to provoke war between Earth and Draconia.
某个第三方团体正试图挑起地球与龙族的战争
You are both being duped.
你们两边都被欺骗了
Take them away.
把他们带走
Just a minute, please.
请等一下
Why should a third party wish to do this?
为什么某个第三方团体想干这个
I've no idea, Madam,
我不知道，夫人
but believe me, that is what is happening.
但相信我，这就是真相
Take them away.
把他们带走
Now please listen to me! If you don't
现在请听我说! 如果你不听的话
you'll be involved in a war
that could cause the death of millions.
你们就会卷入一场战争，百万生灵将因此丧命
Is this the evidence upon which you accuse me?
这就是你们控诉我的证据?
I must ask you to convey a formal protest to your Emperor.
我必须要求你向你的皇帝转达我们的正式抗议
I shall inform him of this latest insult
to the honour of the Draconian empire.
我会告诉他的，告诉他你们对龙族尊严的侮辱
But why?
不过为什么?
Why should they produce such an elaborate lie?
为什么要编造一个如此复杂的谎言
The ways of the Earthmen are devious.
They're an inscrutable species.
地球人的行为很怪异，他们这个种族真是难以揣测
Obviously, they are preparing the next stage of their plan.
很显然，他们在为他们自己计划的下一步铺路
First, the attacks on our ships and now this.
首先，攻击我们的船，然后又是这个
Is it possible, Your Highness,
that for once the Earthmen spoke the truth?
有没有可能，殿下，这一次地球人说的是事实?
Some plan of the Emperor
of which Your Highness has not been informed?
皇帝有他自己的计划，而没有告知殿下?
The Emperor would not possibly contemplate such a plan.
我们的皇帝不会弄出这样的计划
We do not break the treaty of peace.
我们不能打破和平协定
Shall I prepare your Excellency's report
to the Emperor on this meeting?
我可以去准备报告了吗，您觐见皇帝陛下时的报告
I must have more information.
我必须获得更多的信息
It would be useful to question
the humans who were found on the ship.
如果能审讯一下船上找到的那两个人，应该会有帮助
They are supposed to be prisoners.
他们肯定被囚禁起来了
Prisoners have been known to escape, Your Highness.
被囚禁的人都是可以逃走的，殿下
Not without help.
那得有人帮忙才行
And that would be a grave act of hostility.
而这可是严重的敌对行为
I could not possibly countenance such a plan.
我不可能支持这样的计划
But, should two escaping prisoners seek sanctuary in this embassy,
但是，如果两个逃犯到大使馆来寻求庇护
it would be uncivilised to turn them away.
我们弃而不管就太不人道了
I must not detain you longer.
我就不再耽搁你了
No doubt you have duties demanding your attention?
无疑你现在还有更需要你关注的事情?
Your Highness.
殿下
WILLIAMS: Well, Doctor, shall we try again?
怎样，博士，我们再试试?
You can suit yourself.
请自便
But I warn you, you're wasting your time.
但我警告你，你是在浪费自己的时间
(MIND PROBE BEEPING)
Are you a member of the Draconian Secret Service?
你是不是龙族特勤组的一员?
No.
不是
No change in the rhythm, sir. He must be telling the truth.
没有波动，他说的应该是实话
How did you get on the cargo ship?
你怎么到货船上去的?
(DOCTOR SIGHING)
I came here in my own ship, the TARDIS.
我是坐着我自己的飞船过去的，TARDIS
- TARDIS? - Yes, my own spaceship.
- TARDIS? - 是的 我的飞船
(MIND PROBE BEEPING)
Why did you help the Draconians attack the cargo ship?
为什么你们要帮助龙族人攻击那艘货船?
DOCTOR: I didn't.
我没有
In any case, it wasn't the Draconians, it was the Ogrons.
而且，那也不是龙族人，是 Ogrons
(WILLIAMS SIGHING)
Your machine can't be working properly. Or else he's controlling it.
你的机器工作不正常，要不然就是他可以控制它
We've checked all the circuits, sir. Those are his thoughts.
我们都检查过所有线路了，先生. 这就是他的想法
We know this man is a Draconian agent. He must be lying.
我们知道这个人是一个龙族特工，他肯定在撒谎
Perhaps he's already been brainwashed, sir.
或许他已经被洗脑了，先生
But as far as he's concerned, what he's telling us is the truth.
但就他现在而言，他告诉我们的是实情
Then we must break through his conditioning.
那我们必须攻破他的防线
Unless you tell me the truth, the real truth,
除非你告诉我们实情，真正的实情
I shall be forced to use increased power.
我只能被迫加大功率了
I wouldn't do that, old man.
我也不愿意这么做，老头
I know these machines. They aren't awfully reliable, you know?
我了解这些机器，他们并不是太可靠，知道不?
You'd do better to worry about the effects on your mind.
你还是操心一下它对你的影响吧
There's just no telling some people, is there, my dear?
有些人就是完全没有判断力，是吧
Step up the power.
调大功率
Increase to 12.
加大到12
Now!
现在!
(BEEPING INTENSIFIES)
Are you an agent of the Draconians?
你是龙族特工吗?
- DOCTOR: No. - When do they plan to attack us?
- 不是   - 他们打算什么时候开始攻击?
They don't.
他们不会
- How did you board the cargo ship? - Through the TARDIS.
- 你是如何到货船上去的? - 通过 TARDIS
- Who first recruited you to serve the Draconians? - No one.
- 谁招募你服务于龙族人的?   - 没谁
WILLIAMS: Who are the other Draconian agents on Earth?
地球上的龙族特工都还有谁?
I don't know.
我不知道
WILLIAMS: The truth, man. I want the truth.
实情，我要的实情
- I'm telling you the truth. - WILLIAMS: I will get the truth.
- 我说的就是实情    - 我会得到实情的
(MIND PROBE BEEPING RAPIDLY)
(MIND PROBE SPARKING)
Doctor, are you sure you're all right?
博士，你确定你没事吗?
Mmm-hmm, apart from a bit of a headache.
当然，只是有一点头疼
I like the new outfit. Who are you fighting tonight?
我对结果挺满意. 你今晚在跟谁斗?
(JO CHUCKLING)
What happened to you, anyway?
你那边发生了什么?
Oh, they kept going on at me to confess.
哦，他们一直逼迫我坦白
Yeah, it's awkward, isn't it?
是，很难堪啊，对不?
Well, they've made up their minds, you see.
他们自己的想法早就先入为主了，你看
They'll only believe us if we tell them what they want to hear.
只有我们说他们想听的，他们才会相信我们
It's a pity really that the Ogrons didn't succeed in kidnapping us.
Ogrons 没能成功绑架我们，还真是遗憾啊
Perhaps we should have been more helpful.
也许那样我们还能更有用一些
- Why?  - Well, if they had succeeded,
- 为什么 - 这样，如果他们成功了
presumably they'd have taken us to where the TARDIS is.
应该说来他们会把我们带到 TARDIS 所在之处
(SIGHING) I'm sorry, Jo,
抱歉，Jo
but I'm afraid another kidnapping attempt is our only ray of hope.
不过恐怕再来一次绑架才是我们唯一的希望
So, we just sit around here waiting for
those jolly old Ogrons to turn up again?
所以，我们就只能干坐在这里，等着那些搞笑的 Ogrons 出现?
(CHUCKLING) That's about it, yes.
正是如此
The President wants to see you. Get moving.
总统要见你，走吧
Not you. You.
不是你，是你
This maybe your chance. Good luck.
这可能是你的机会，好运
- See you later. - Bye.
- 晚些见   - 拜
(DOOR CLOSING)
I'm giving you a final chance to tell me the truth.
我给你最后一次机会，你告诉我真相
Madam President,
总统夫人
I've been telling you the truth for some considerable time
我一直在告诉你真相，颇有一段时间了
but you just won't believe me.
但你就是我相信我
I can't think why you chose to work for the Draconians.
我想不通你为什么选择去为龙族人卖命
But whatever it is, I'll double any offer they've made to you.
不管怎样吧，他们给你许诺了什么，我都加倍
That's very generous of you, madam,
夫人，您真是慷慨
but you'd only be buying information that doesn't exist.
但这是在买不存在的信息
You leave me no alternative.
你让我没有选择了
Under the powers invested in me by the Special Security Act,
根据特别安全法案授权于我的权力
I'm sending you to the Lunar Penal Colony.
我现在发配你去月球刑事殖民地
What, without a trial?
什么，不进行审判吗?
Without even a chance to state my case?
甚至都不给我一个陈述的机会?
So, you're just tucking me quietly away, are you?
你们就这样把我悄悄地处理了，是吧?
What about my companion?
我的同伴会怎样?
She will remain here.
她将留在这里
I have hopes that, away from your influence,
我还是有所期待，远离了你的影响
I might be able to make her see the error of her ways.
我也许能让她看明白她走错了路
But you will see that she comes to no harm?
但你可否盯着点，让她免受伤害?
We are not barbarians.
我们不是野蛮人
If you want to help her,
如果你想帮她,
why don't you tell me where she comes from?
为什么不告诉我她来自哪里?
I'd like to inform her family.
我好通知她的家人
I'd like to, madam.
我也期望如此，夫人
I really would, but there's nothing that I can say that you'd believe.
我真的这样，但确实我说不出什么你能相信的东西
May I say goodbye to her?
我可以跟她道个别吗?
No! You'll be leaving immediately for the penal colony.
不，你要立刻出发去刑事殖民地
We're putting you where your Draconian friends will be unable to reach you.
我们要把你放到你那些龙族朋友够不到你的地方
Penny for them, Miss Grant?
想什么呢 (?)，Grant 小姐?
You! What are you doing here?
你! 你在这里干什么?
To coin a phrase, I've come to take you away from all this.
简单地说，我来带你远离这一切
What are you talking about?
你这是什么意思
Well, surely you don't want to spend the rest of your life in here, do you?
你当然不会期望在这里过完你的下半辈子，是吧?
Well, I'm not going anywhere with you, that's for sure.
这是当然. 但我也不打算同你去任何地方
Oh, but you are, you know.
你会的，知道吗
Believe it or not,
不管你信不信
I am a fully accredited commissioner from the planet Sirius 4
我现在是天狼星4号的完全授权的专员
and you and the Doctor are two dangerous criminals
而你和博士是两个危险的罪犯
being handed over into my custody.
要转交到我的手中
So it was you!
原来是你!
You ordered those Ogrons to attack the ships
是你命令了那些 Ogrons 来攻击那艘货船
and pretend they were Draconians!
还让他们假装是龙族人!
But, of course!
不过，当然了
Those lumbering idiots could never have thought up
那些愚蠢的家伙是无论如何也想不出
such a brilliant scheme by themselves.
如此天才的计划的
Why did you want to start a war?
你为什么要挑起一场战争?
Now, come on, Miss Grant, be reasonable.
得了，Grant 小姐，理性一点
You want to see the Doctor again, don't you?
你还想再见到博士的，对吧?
- Where is he? - He's in another prison, on the Moon.
- 他在哪儿?  - 他现在在另外一个监狱，月球上
We're going to collect him.
我们要去接他
How do I know you're telling the truth?
我怎么知道你说的是不是实话?
You don't.
你不知道
And the only way you'll find out is by coming with me.
唯一搞明白的方法就是跟我走
Well?
怎样
(SIGHING)
How did you know we were here in the first place?
你怎么知道我们在这里的?
Well, after they'd attacked the cargo ships,
啊，当那些 Ogrons 攻击了那艘货船之后
the Ogrons returned to their planet, taking their loot with them.
他们带着战利品，回到自己的星球
Now imagine my surprise, and my delight,
想想一下我的惊讶，还有喜悦
when I found that they brought me the Doctor's TARDIS.
我发现他们带回来了博士的 TARDIS
And why are you taking us with you?
那你现在为什么要让我们跟你走?
Oh, need you ask?
哦，这还需要说?
How could I leave two dear friends in such dire straits?
我怎么可能把两个亲爱的朋友留在这么恐怖的地方?
Oh, you don't seriously think that
哦，你才不是这么想的
I'm going to believe that you want to help us...
我都要相信你是想帮助我们...
Believe what you like, Miss Grant, I have my reasons.
不管你信不信，Grant 小姐，我有我的理由
Now, are you coming,
现在，你是跟着走呢?
or do you really wish to vegetate in
this hole for the rest of your natural?
还是打算真在这个洞里耗完下半辈子?
Very well. I'll come.
好吧，我去
Excellent!
太棒了!
The prisoner and I are ready to leave now, guard.
囚犯和我打算现在离开，守卫
Anywhere is better than here.
任何地方都比这里好
- Hello, Jo. - Doctor!
- 嘿，Jo  - 博士!
- How are you? All right? - Well...
- 你怎么样? 没事吧?  - 这个...
Right, they'll be plenty of time
for the exchange of social pleasantries.
好啦，他们有足够的时间来嘘寒问暖
Put him inside.
把他关进去
Thank you, gentlemen. You can leave them to me now.
谢谢你们，先生们. 你们可以把他们俩留给我了
Well, Doctor, this is an interesting reversal.
怎样，博士，这真是有趣的反转啊
I remember your once visiting me when I was in prison.
我记得有一次我在监狱里面你还来探访
You know, I'd very much like to know why...
你知道吗，我倒是很想知道为什么...
Why you've been locked up?
为什么你被锁起来了?
No, why I'm still alive.
不，为什么我还活着
Oh, come, your health is very precious to me, for the moment.
哦，得了，你的健康对我来说很珍贵的，至少目前是
You see, my employers are most interested in you.
要知道，我的雇主对你非常有兴趣
- The Ogrons? - Miss Grant, please! I employ them.
- 是 Ogrons?  - Grant 小姐，是我雇佣他们好不
Yes, well, whatever it is you're up to,
you needn't expect any help from me.
好吧，不管你的图谋是什么，别想从我这里得到帮助
I don't need any help.
我不需要任何帮助
Your simple presence will be quite enough.
你们只要出现就完全够了
Oh, by the way, I need hardly warn you
there is no point in trying to escape.
哦，对了，不需要我警告你吧，企图在这里逃跑完全没意义
This is an interplanetary police spaceship,
这是一艘星际警用飞船
specially built for carrying prisoners, as you can see.
专为运送囚犯建造的，你可以看得出来
Stolen, of course?
偷来的，对吧?
(SCOFFING) Of course. Oh, and another thing...
当然. 哦，还有一件事
There's a closed-circuit television
camera trained on you from up there,
这里有一个闭路电视摄像头，对准了你
so you will be under continuous observation.
所以你在我的持续监视之下
I think that's all.
差不多就是这些了
Well, now, if you'll excuse me,
现在，如果没有什么事情
I have some rather complicated
astro-navigational calculations to work out.
我还要去做一些复杂的航天导航计算
May I ask where we're going?
我能问问我们要去哪儿吗?
Certainly. To the home of our friends, the Ogrons.
当然可以，去我们朋友的家乡，那些 Ogrons 的
A barren and uninteresting planet
on the remote fringes of the galaxy.
一颗贫瘠而无趣的星球，在遥远的星系边缘
Why are you taking us there?
你为什么带我去那里?
That, Miss Grant, you will discover when you arrive.
这个，Grant 小姐，你到了就知道了
Right, now listen to me. We haven't got much time
好了，现在听我说，我们没有太多时间
before he gets back to the flight deck.
要赶在他回到飞行舱之前
Now, the first thing we've got to do is to escape.
现在第一件事我们要做的事情是逃脱
Now, they took my sonic screwdriver from me in the prison
在监狱的时候他们把我的音速起子给拿走了
but they didn't get a hold of this.
不过他们没发现这个
- A steel file.   - Right, let's go.
- 一把锉刀?   - 对，我们开始
No, not yet. Let's wait till he gets back to the flight deck,
不，还不行. 先等他回到飞行舱
then he'll set the controls. Now, this is an automatic spaceship.
等他设定好控制，飞船就进入自动巡航状态了
Once we're underway, the computers take over, right?
等我们一启程，电脑就完全接管了，对吧
-Okay, so what's the plan?
-Now this is what we're gonna do.
- 好了，计划是什么  - 我们接下来要这样
So I told the High Council of the Time Lords,
于是我就告诉时间领主最高理事会
I said they had absolutely no right
to put me on trial in the first place.
我说他们一开始就完全无权让我受审
Well, if I chose to go wandering around the universe in my own time,
就是说，如果我自己决定要用我自己的时间去宇宙里四处逛逛
that was my business.
那是我自己的事情
What about stealing the TARDIS?
那偷 TARDIS 的事情怎么说?
I didn't steal it. I just borrowed it.
我没偷，我是借走的
I fully intended to return it, I assure you.
我本来就打算还回去的，我向你保证
Anyway, she wasn't exactly the latest model, poor old thing.
再说了，它也不是最新的型号，可怜的老古董
JO: (LAUGHING) You can say that again.
你又说这个
I tell you, I made a complete fool of that prosecuting council, though.
我跟你说，我把他们检察委员会从头到尾给耍了
I ridiculed his every argument.
我把他的每句话都驳倒了
Yes, and I told him that I had the complete answer
是的，我跟他说我全有理由
to every one his charges against me.
对于他指控我的每一条
JO: And then what happened?
然后发生了什么
DOCTOR: Then what happened, well, they found me guilty,
然后发生了什么，这个，他们说我有罪
changed my appearance and exiled me to Earth.
改变了我的外形，把我流放到了地球
JO: And that's where you met me!
就是你碰见我的地方!
That's right. That's where I met you.
对，就是我碰见你的地方
And that alone made the exile worthwhile, Miss Grant.
单单这个就让这次流放变得有价值了，Grant 小姐
JO: Thank you!
谢谢你!
Not that there's anything wrong with Earth.
不过地球本身也没有什么问题
Well, it's quite a nice, little planet in its own way, but...
嗯，它很不错，小小的星球，有自己的风格，不过...
After all, I am a Time Lord, Jo,
and I think I've deserve my freedom.
毕竟，我是一个时间领主，Jo, 我想我应该享有我的自由
-JO: Right!
-In reminiscent mood, are you, Doctor?
- 对啊   - 又想忆苦思甜了，是吗，博士?
Poor Miss Grant, you have my deepest sympathy.
可怜的 Grant 小姐，我对你深表同情
(CHUCKLING)
As I soon realised, the trouble with Lethbridge-Stewart
我很快就发现，Lethbridge-Stewart 准将的问题是
is that he's got a military mind.
他始终是军人的思维
Well, he is a brigadier, after all. I mean, what do you expect?
但是，毕竟他是一个准将啊. 我是说，你还想他怎么样?
No, that's just the trouble though.
不，那还只是问题的开始
He's hidebound, you see. He always does everything by the rules.
他很死板，你明白吗. 他总是按照规则来做事情
I keep telling him. I said, "There are times, you know,
我一直跟他说: "有些时候啊，
"when you've simply got to cut right through the red tape."
你就得抛弃那些繁文缛节
And you've managed to do that, have you?
你就真这样做了，是吗
DOCTOR: Yes, I've managed to cut right through it.
是的，我就抛掉这些东西
And I'm not going to let authority stand between me and my freedom.
我可不打算让当局挡住我去追求自由
(SIGHING) Lethbridge-Stewart, I...
Lethbridge-Stewart, 我...
Hey! As far as he's concerned
I've been absent without leave all this time.
说到他，我还没有跟他请假就离开了
I'm always telling people ...
我一直跟人说...
Is everything all right, Miss Grant?
Yes, yes, I'm fine.
And how about you, Doctor?
No ill effects, I hope?
Doctor, are you all right?
JO: Please don't wake him.
Is he? How very relaxed of him.
you come with me, Miss Grant.
Come on!
Right, in you go, Miss Grant.
Can you hear me, Doctor?
Are you on the flight deck?
If so, listen to this.
Miss Grant is in the air lock.
Unless you surrender yourself
to me immediately,
I shall open the outer door
and hurl her into space.
What an ingenious fellow
you are, Doctor!
Oh, no, you don't!
Now hold it, Doctor, hold it!
Get that blaster over to me
or I press this button,
and that will be the end of Miss Grant!
(DOCTOR EXCLAIMING)
Thank you, Doctor.
(THUDDING)
Well, we appear to have company.
Would these be your Ogron friends?
Why, no, no.
Well, I should try and be
a bit more hospitable, old chap.
Come on, put that gun away.
They've probably got us outnumbered.
Welcome on board my ship.
To what do I owe the honour?
Why have you violated
the Draconian frontier?
Uh, yes, I'm most apologetic about that,
but it was really beyond my control.
You see, my prisoners
were trying to escape and my...
-My ship was thrown off course.
-Prisoners?
Yes, I am the commissioner
of Earth's Interplanetary Police.
I'm taking these two people back
to planet Sirius 4 for...for trial.
Uh, here is my warrant of authority.
Now, don't believe this man, he's lying.
I'm not concerned in disputes
between Earthmen.
We shall take them to Draconia.
Put them in the cage.
But you can't do that!
I'm a commissioner
of Interplanetary Police!
This is my spaceship!
I tell you, you can't do that!
Well, personally I'm quite happy
to be going to Draconia, Jo.
Perhaps we can convince the Emperor
what our friend here
has been trying to do.
You really think he'd believe you?
Well, this won't be my first visit
to Draconia, you know?
Many years ago,
I spent quite some time there.
I was able to help them through a period
of very great difficulty.
So there's a good chance
that they'll believe you, huh?
Well, it was a long time ago.
Things may have changed.
But I do understand
the Draconian mentality, Jo.
It all depends how you approach them.
So, if they do believe the Doctor,
you've had it!
Perhaps, Miss Grant, perhaps.
But one never knows
when help may be at hand.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I think that this is going to be
rather a long journey,
so, uh, good night.
We'll wake you with a cup of tea
in the morning.
- Hello, Jo. - Doctor!
- 嘿, Jo  - 博士!
- How are you? All right? - Well...
- 你怎么样? 没事吧?  - 这个...
Right, they'll be plenty of time
for the exchange of social pleasantries.
好啦, 他们有足够的时间来嘘寒问暖
Put him inside.
把他关进去
Thank you, gentlemen. You can leave them to me now.
谢谢你们, 先生们. 你们可以把他们俩留给我了
Well, Doctor, this is an interesting reversal.
怎样, 博士, 这真是有趣的反转啊
I remember your once visiting me when I was in prison.
我记得有一次我在监狱里面你还来探访
You know, I'd very much like to know why...
你知道吗, 我倒是很想知道为什么...
Why you've been locked up?
为什么你被锁起来了?
No, why I'm still alive.
不, 为什么我还活着
Oh, come, your health is very precious to me, for the moment.
哦, 得了, 你的健康对我来说很珍贵的, 至少目前是
You see, my employers are most interested in you.
要知道, 我的雇主对你非常有兴趣
- The Ogrons? - Miss Grant, please! I employ them.
- 是 Ogrons?  - Grant 小姐, 是我雇佣他们好不
Yes, well, whatever it is you're up to,
you needn't expect any help from me.
好吧, 不管你的图谋是什么, 别想从我这里得到帮助
I don't need any help.
我不需要任何帮助
Your simple presence will be quite enough.
你们只要出现就完全够了
Oh, by the way, I need hardly warn you
there is no point in trying to escape.
哦, 对了, 不需要我警告你吧, 企图在这里逃跑完全没意义
This is an interplanetary police spaceship,
这是一艘星际警用飞船
specially built for carrying prisoners, as you can see.
专为运送囚犯建造的, 你可以看得出来
Stolen, of course?
偷来的, 对吧?
(SCOFFING) Of course. Oh, and another thing...
当然. 哦, 还有一件事
There's a closed-circuit television
camera trained on you from up there,
这里有一个闭路电视摄像头, 对准了你
so you will be under continuous observation.
所以你在我的持续监视之下
I think that's all.
差不多就是这些了
Well, now, if you'll excuse me,/
现在, 如果没有什么事情
I have some rather complicated
astro-navigational calculations to work out.
我还要去做一些复杂的航天导航计算
May I ask where we're going?
我能问问我们要去哪儿吗?
Certainly. To the home of our friends, the Ogrons.
当然可以, 去我们朋友的家乡, 那些 Ogrons 的
A barren and uninteresting planet
on the remote fringes of the galaxy.
一颗贫瘠而无趣的星球, 在遥远的星系边缘
Why are you taking us there?
你为什么带我去那里?
That, Miss Grant, you will discover when you arrive.
这个, Grant 小姐, 你到了就知道了
Right, now listen to me. We haven't got much time
好了, 现在听我说, 我们没有太多时间
before he gets back to the flight deck.
要赶在他回到飞行舱之前
Now, the first thing we've got to do is to escape.
现在第一件事我们要做的事情是逃脱
Now, they took my sonic screwdriver from me in the prison
在监狱的时候他们把我的音速起子给拿走了
but they didn't get a hold of this.
不过他们没发现这个
- A steel file.   - Right, let's go.
- 一把锉刀?   - 对, 我们开始
No, not yet. Let's wait till he gets back to the flight deck,
不, 还不行. 先等他回到飞行舱
then he'll set the controls. Now, this is an automatic spaceship.
等他设定好控制, 飞船就进入自动巡航状态了
Once we're underway, the computers take over, right?
等我们一启程, 电脑就完全接管了, 对吧
-Okay, so what's the plan?
-Now this is what we're gonna do.
- 好了, 计划是什么  - 我们接下来要这样
So I told the High Council of the Time Lords,
于是我就告诉时间领主最高理事会
I said they had absolutely no right
to put me on trial in the first place.
我说他们一开始就完全无权让我受审
Well, if I chose to go wandering around the universe in my own time,
就是说, 如果我自己决定要用我自己的时间去宇宙里四处逛逛
that was my business.
那是我自己的事情
What about stealing the TARDIS?
那偷 TARDIS 的事情怎么说?
I didn't steal it. I just borrowed it.
我没偷, 我是借走的
I fully intended to return it, I assure you.
我本来就打算还回去的, 我向你保证
Anyway, she wasn't exactly the latest model, poor old thing.
再说了, 它也不是最新的型号, 可怜的老古董
JO: (LAUGHING) You can say that again.
你又说这个
I tell you, I made a complete fool of that prosecuting council, though.
我跟你说, 我把他们检察委员会从头到尾给耍了
I ridiculed his every argument.
我把他的每句话都驳倒了
Yes, and I told him that I had the complete answer
是的, 我跟他说我全有理由
to every one his charges against me.
对于他指控我的每一条
JO: And then what happened?
然后发生了什么
DOCTOR: Then what happened, well, they found me guilty,
然后发生了什么, 这个, 他们说我有罪
changed my appearance and exiled me to Earth.
改变了我的外形, 把我流放到了地球
JO: And that's where you met me!
就是你碰见我的地方!
That's right. That's where I met you.
对, 就是我碰见你的地方
And that alone made the exile worthwhile, Miss Grant.
单单这个就让这次流放变得有价值了, Grant 小姐
JO: Thank you!
谢谢你!
Not that there's anything wrong with Earth.
不过地球本身也没有什么问题
Well, it's quite a nice, little planet in its own way, but...
嗯, 它很不错, 小小的星球, 有自己的风格, 不过...
After all, I am a Time Lord, Jo,
and I think I've deserve my freedom.
毕竟, 我是一个时间领主, Jo, 我想我应该享有我的自由
-JO: Right!
-In reminiscent mood, are you, Doctor?
对啊, 又在回忆了, 是吗, 博士?
Poor Miss Grant, you have my deepest sympathy.
可怜的 Grant 小姐, 我对你深表同情
(CHUCKLING)
As I soon realised, the trouble with Lethbridge-Stewart
我很快就发现, Lethbridge-Stewart 准将的问题是
is that he's got a military mind.
他始终是军人的思维
Well, he is a brigadier, after all. I mean, what do you expect?
但是, 毕竟他是一个准将啊. 我是说, 你还想他怎么样?
No, that's just the trouble though.
不, 那还只是问题的开始
He's hidebound, you see. He always does everything by the rules.
他很死板, 你明白吗. 他总是按照规则来做事情
I keep telling him. I said, "There are times, you know,
我一直跟他说: "有些时候啊,
"when you've simply got to cut right through the red tape."
你就得抛弃那些繁文缛节
And you've managed to do that, have you?
你就真这样做了, 是吗
DOCTOR: Yes, I've managed to cut right through it.
是的, 我就抛掉这些东西
And I'm not going to let authority stand between me and my freedom.
我可不打算让当局挡住我去追求自由
(SIGHING) Lethbridge-Stewart, I...
Lethbridge-Stewart, 我...
Hey! As far as he's concerned
I've been absent without leave all this time.
说到他, 我还没有跟他请假就离开了
I'm always telling people ...
我一直跟人说...
Is everything all right, Miss Grant?
一切都还好吗，Grant 小姐？
Yes, yes, I'm fine.
是的是的，我很好
And how about you, Doctor?
No ill effects, I hope?
你怎么样，博士。没什么不舒服吧，但愿？
Doctor, are you all right?
博士，你没事吧？
JO: Please don't wake him.
请不要吵醒他
Is he? How very relaxed of him.
是吧？他心还挺宽啊
You come with me, Miss Grant.
你跟我来，Grant 小姐
Come on!
过来！
Right, in you go, Miss Grant.
好了，进去吧你，Grant 小姐
Can you hear me, Doctor?
你能听到吗，博士？
Are you on the flight deck?
If so, listen to this.
你是在飞行甲板上吗？如果是，听好了
Miss Grant is in the air lock.
Grant 小姐在气闸里
Unless you surrender yourself
to me immediately,
除非你立刻向我投降
I shall open the outer door
and hurl her into space.
否则我打开外门把她抛进太空去
What an ingenious fellow you are, Doctor!
你真是个聪明的家伙，博士
Oh, no, you don't!
噢，别
Now hold it, Doctor, hold it!
现在住手，博士，住手
Get that blaster over to me
or I press this button,
把枪递给我，否则我按按钮了
and that will be the end of Miss Grant!
那样的话 Grant 小姐就玩完了！
(DOCTOR EXCLAIMING)
Thank you, Doctor.
谢谢你，博士
(THUDDING)
Well, we appear to have company.
哦，看来我们有同伴了
Would these be your Ogron friends?
会是你的那些 Orgron 朋友吗？
Why, no, no.
为什么，不不
Well, I should try and be
a bit more hospitable, old chap.
那，我就会尽量好客一点，老伙计
Come on, put that gun away.
They've probably got us outnumbered.
得了，扔掉那把枪吧。他们很可能比我们人多
Welcome on board my ship.
To what do I owe the honour?
欢迎来到我的飞船。是谁带给我这份荣幸呢？
Why have you violated
the Draconian frontier?
你们为什么犯我龙族边界？
Uh, yes, I'm most apologetic about that,
but it was really beyond my control.
啊，是，我对此非常抱歉。不过情况真的超出了我的控制
You see, my prisoners
were trying to escape and my...
你看，这两个囚犯试图逃走，而我的...
- My ship was thrown off course.
- Prisoners?
- 我的飞船又被抛出了航线
- 囚犯？
Yes, I am the commissioner
of Earth's Interplanetary Police.
是的，我是地球星际警局的专员FIXME
I'm taking these two people back
to planet Sirius 4 for...for trial.
我要把这两个人带回天狼星四号，为了...让他们受审
Uh, here is my warrant of authority.
啊，这是我的授权书FIXME
Now, don't believe this man, he's lying.
噢，别相信这个人，他在撒谎
I'm not concerned in disputes
between Earthmen.
我不关心你们地球人相互之间的纠纷
We shall take them to Draconia.
Put them in the cage.
我们要带他们回国去。先把他们关进笼子吧
But you can't do that!
但你不能这么做！
I'm a commissioner
of Interplanetary Police!
我是星际警局的专员FIXME！
This is my spaceship!
I tell you, you can't do that!
这是我的飞船！我跟你说，你不能这么干！
Well, personally I'm quite happy
to be going to Draconia, Jo.
不过呢，我个人倒是非常高兴去龙帝国走一趟，Jo
Perhaps we can convince the Emperor
说不定我们可以说服皇帝
what our friend here has been trying to do.
让他知道我们这位朋友一直在干的事情
You really think he'd believe you?
你真的以为他会相信你？
Well, this won't be my first visit
to Draconia, you know?
哦，这也不是我第一次去龙帝国，你知道不？
Many years ago,
I spent quite some time there.
很多年前，我在那里待了一段时间
I was able to help them through a period
of very great difficulty.
我在他们一段困难的时期帮了些忙
So there's a good chance
that they'll believe you, huh?
所以有很大机会他们会相信你，是吧？
Well, it was a long time ago.
Things may have changed.
不过，那是好久以前，情况也许会变
But I do understand
the Draconian mentality, Jo.
但我倒是明白他们考虑问题的方式，Jo
It all depends how you approach them.
一切都取决于你如何接近他们
So, if they do believe the Doctor,
you've had it!
所以，如果他们相信了博士，你就有好果子吃了
Perhaps, Miss Grant, perhaps.
也许吧，Grant 小姐，也许吧
But one never knows
when help may be at hand.
但人们永远不知道，帮助什么时候就会到来
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I think that this is going to be rather a long journey,/
现在，如果没什么事的话，而我觉得这会是一段不短的旅程
so, uh, good night.
所以，晚安
We'll wake you with a cup of tea
in the morning.
到早上了我们会给你准备一杯茶再叫醒你的
So, Father, once more
Earthmen have invaded our space.
看，父亲，地球人又一次入侵了我们的空间
You will address the Emperor
in a proper manner.
你得先用得体的方式先皇帝致礼
Your pardon.
请您谅解
May I have permission to address the Emperor?
我可以向皇帝致礼吗？
My life at your command.
我听候您的差遣
One day, my Son, you will inherit this throne.
某一天，儿子，你会继承这个宝座
Then you will realise the importance of due formality.
那时你就会明白仪式感的重要性
Now, what do you wish to say?
现在看看，你想要说些什么？
Surely, now you will declare war
upon the Earthmen?
当然。现在你们要向地球人宣战了吗？
Let me lead your battle fleets
to crush their...
让我带领你的战斗舰队去碾压他们的...
They too, have battle fleets, my Son.
他们一样，也有战斗舰队，孩子
Such a war could well bring down both empires.
这样的战争很可能把这两个帝国都摧毁
Not if we strike first,
then we shall be the victors!
如果我们先行出击就不会，我们将会是胜利者！
In such a war, there are no victors.
在这样的战争中, 没有胜利者
The nobles of the court are demanding action.
王廷上的贵族们都要求采取行动
They fear for the honour of Draconia.
他们担心龙帝国的荣誉
I am the emperor!
The honour of Draconia is vested in me.
我是皇帝，龙帝国的荣誉在我这里
The throne depends upon
the great families for support.
皇位也依赖于各大家族的支持
Emperors have been deposed before now.
以前也有皇帝被废掉
An emperor who does not rule
deposes himself!
一个不统治的皇帝就会被遗弃!
Then what will you do, Father?
那你决定怎么做，父亲？
I shall question these Earthmen myself.
我将亲自找这些地球人问话
I have already sent for them.
我已经让人去带他们过来了
Why waste time listening to their lies?
为什么要浪费时间听他们的谎言呢？
Majesty, I bring the prisoners.
陛下，我把囚犯带过来了
May I have permission to address the Emperor?
允许我向皇帝致礼吗？
Wait!
等一下！
This is an insult!
这是种侮辱！
My life at your command, sire.
我听候您的差遣，陛下
How dare you address the Emperor
你怎敢这样向皇帝致礼？
in a manner reserved for a noble of Draconia?
这是龙帝国贵族才可以使用的方式
Ah, but I am a noble of Draconia.
啊，但我是龙帝国贵族
The honour was conferred on me
by the 15th Emperor.
这项荣誉是第十五世皇帝授予我的
The 15th Emperor reigned 500 years ago.
第十五世皇帝是500年前了
(LAUGHING)
Your Majesty, do not be taken
in by this ridiculous story...
陛下，别被这种荒谬的故事给诓进去了
Be silent!
安静！
There is a legend among our people
我们的人当中的确有个传说
of a man who assisted the 15th Emperor
at a time of great trouble
说有个人在十五世皇帝非常困难的时期帮了大忙
when we were almost overwhelmed
by a great plague from outer space.
当时我们被外太空来的一种厉害的瘟疫害得不轻
But you could not be that man.
No Earthman lives so long.
但你不可能是那个人。没有哪个地球人能活那么久
Your Majesty, this man that you speak of,
陛下，你所说的这个人
was he not known as the Doctor?
是不是都叫他博士？
And did he not come to this planet
in a spaceship called the TARDIS?
而且他是乘坐一个叫做 TARDIS 的飞船来到这个星球的？
He did.
是的
Well, I am that man, sire.
对了，我就是那个人，陛下
And I come from a race of people
that live far longer than any Earthman.
我来自另外一个种族，我们比地球人寿命长得多
Even if I accept your claim,
you have broken our law.
即使我接受你宣称的这个身份，你也触犯了法律
Why did you violate Draconian space?
你为什么要侵犯龙帝国边界？
Your Majesty, this man was, and still is, my prisoner.
陛下，这个人本来是我的囚犯，现在也还是
It is true, Your Majesty.
这是真的，陛下
I did come here as a prisoner,
but I came willingly,
我的确是以囚犯身份来到这里的，但愿意过来
in order to inform you that
this man is plotting a war
只是为了告诉你们，这个人试图挑起一场战争
between Earth and Draconia!
以让地球和龙帝国两败俱伤！
All Earthmen are determined upon war.
所有地球人都铁了心要一场战争
Ah, but the Master is not an Earthman.
是，但这位法师不是地球人
I'm sorry to have to admit it,
but he's a renegade of my own race
我不得不惭愧地承认，他是我那个种族中的败类
and he's using creatures called Ogrons
他利用了一种叫做 Ogrons 的生物
to attack your spaceships and those of the Earthmen.
攻击了你们和那些地球人的飞船
The Earthmen who attacked our spaceships,
那些袭击过我们的地球人
they have been seen many times.
之前也被看到过很多次
I'm sorry, but there you are in error, sir.
抱歉，你们搞错了，阁下
Your people have seen Ogrons,
你们的人看见的是 Ogrons
but they appear to them as Earthmen
because of a hypnotic device.
但你们以为你们看见的是地球人，这都是因为一种致幻装置
It's true, Your Majesty.
这是真的，陛下
When the Ogrons attacked the Earth ships,
当 Ogrons 攻击地球飞船的时候
the Earthmen saw them as Draconians.
地球人看他们就是龙族人
Silence! Females are not permitted
to speak in the presence of the Emperor.
安静！女人不允许在皇帝面前说话
Your Majesty, do not be deceived
by the pathetic ravings
陛下, 不要被这些可悲的胡言乱语欺骗了
of two criminals trying to evade justice.
这两个罪犯只是试图逃避法律制裁
If what you say is true, it would explain much.
如果你说的是真的，那很多东西就解释得通了
We lived at peace with the Earthmen
for many years,
我们跟地球人和平共处了这么多年
then suddenly they began to raid our spaceships.
他们突然间就开始攻击我们的飞船了
When we protested, they said that we were attacking them.
我们提出抗议的时候，他们又说是我们在攻击他们
In order to cover up their own attacks!
他们是在掩盖他们自己的攻击行为！
This is simply a plot of the Earthmen
to lull us into false security.
这只是地球人的阴谋, 让我们陷入虚假的安全
Speak!
说！
Your Majesty, a spaceship from Earth
陛下，地球来了一艘飞船
seeks permission to land in the palace spaceport.
请求降落在皇家空港
They say they're on a special mission
from the President of Earth.
他们说他们在执行地球总统授命的一项特殊任务
This is a trick! You must not allow them to land!
这是个骗局！你不能让他们着陆！
We are not yet at war with Earth.
我们跟地球还没开战
I shall hear what their president has to say.
我要听听他们的总统有什么可说的
I give my permission.
我给他们许可
Your Majesty.
陛下
A wise decision, Your Majesty.
一个明智的决定，陛下
For only by Earth and Draconia
working together
只有地球和龙帝国一起努力
can we hope to arrive at the truth.
我们才有期望得到真相
I, too, welcome your wisdom,
Your Majesty.
我赞同你智慧的决策，陛下
Nobody could be more devoted
to the cause of peace than I.
没有人比我更热衷于和平事业
As a commissioner of Earth's
Interplanetary Police,
作为地球的星际警局专员
I have devoted my life to the cause of law and order.
我把我的一生都献给了法律和秩序事业
And law and order can only exist
in a time of peace.
而法律和秩序只能在和平的时代存在
You feeling all right, old chap?
你感觉还好吗, 老伙计？
Only during a period of social stability,
只有在社会稳定时期，
can society adequately deal with criminals
社会才能有力打击罪犯
such as this man and this unfortunate girl.
就像这个人和这个不幸女孩儿这样的罪犯
(HYPNOTIC PULSE SOUNDING)
Doctor, listen! That sound!
博士，听！那个声音！
PRINCE: Silence, female!
安静，女人！
Quiet!
安静！
It's the same noise that I heard on the cargo ship.
这和我在货船上听到的声音是一样的
Doctor, it's the Ogrons!
博士，是 Ogrons！
Your Majesty, I beg of you to be cautious.
陛下，我请求你小心行事
Something is seriously wrong here.
This ship that has just landed,
这里有些事非常不对劲。刚刚降落的那艘飞船，
I beg you, place it under guard immediately.
我请求你，把它纳入警戒控制之内
Your Majesty, please?
陛下，可以吗？
DRACONIAN: (SHOUTING) Earthmen!
地球人！
MASTER: Seize them, fool!
抓住它们，笨蛋！
(ALL GRUNTING)
Ah, you idiots! Back to the ship, all of you!
啊，这群笨蛋！回到船上去吧，你们全部！
Come on, back to the ship!
快点，回到船上去！
Now will you believe
in the treachery of the Earthmen?
现在你相信地球人会背信弃义吧？
Your Majesty, look down here
and tell me, what do you see?
陛下，往下看看，告诉我，你看到的是什么？
(HYPNOTIC PULSE SOUNDING)
I see one of your Earth soldiers
我看到了一个你们的地球士兵
who attacked my palace and killed my people.
是他攻击我皇宫、杀我族人
Jo? Jo, can you still hear that sound?
Jo? 你还能听到那声音吗？
(HYPNOTIC PULSE FADING)
Yes, it's fading. It's almost gone.
是的，不过小了，基本听不到了
Your Majesty, I beg of you, please.
Look again.
陛下，我请求你，再看一眼
Why do we delay? Destroy him!
还耽搁什么？消灭他！
Wait!
等等！
He has spoken the truth.
他说的是实情
Great, lumbering idiots!
很好，蠢笨的家伙！
Now you tell me that you've left
one of your fellows in the palace!
现在你跟说你把一个家伙留在皇宫里了!
Do you realise what this means?
你知道这意味着什么吗？
As soon as the effect
of the hypno-sound wears off,
一旦催眠声音的效果消失了
the Draconians will know
who it really was who attacked them.
龙族人就会知道真正是谁攻击了他们
You've ruined everything!
你们坏了所有的事！
What shall we do now?
我们现在该怎么办？
Do? There's only one thing we can do.
办？只有一件事我们能办
Make sure that the Doctor and his evidence
确保博士和他的证据...
is never allowed to reach Earth.
绝对到不了地球！
Why does the Master want war
between Earth and Draconia?
为什么法师想要让地球和龙帝国之间发生战争？
Did you attack our spaceships
and those of the Earthmen?
是你攻击了我们的飞船吗？地球人的呢？
Oh, it's no good. We're not getting anywhere.
噢，这样没用。我们什么也问不出来
Let me take him for questioning.
He will answer to me.
让我把他带去问话吧，他会告诉我的
I shall use the mind probe.
我将使用思维探测器
You'd only be wasting your time.
你这只是在浪费时间
The Ogrons have got the finest
defence mechanism of all, stupidity.
They haven't got a mind
for you to probe.
Then remove him.
We will deal with him later.
Why did that sound make us see
this creature as a soldier from Earth?
为什么那个声音会让我们把这个生物看成是来自地球的士兵？
Because you're frightened of Earthmen.
因为你们害怕地球人
Draconians fear nothing, female.
龙族人什么也不怕，女人
Well, of course you do.
You fear them and they fear you.
得了，你们当然怕，你们怕他们，他们怕你们
That's why when Earthmen heard that sound, they saw Draconians.
这就是为什么当地球人听到这个声音时, 他们看到了龙族人
That is true.
说得没错
We do fear the Earthmen and they fear us.
我们害怕地球人，他们也怕我们
And fear breeds hatred, Your Majesty.
而恐惧滋生仇恨，陛下
Fear is the greatest enemy of them all, for fear leads us to war.
恐惧是最大的敌人，因为恐惧导致我们走向战争
We shall tell the Earthmen
what has happened here.
我们要告诉地球人这里发生了什么
They, too, must know the truth.
他们也得知道真相
They will not believe us.
他们不会相信我们的
The Prince is right, Your Majesty.
王子是对的，陛下
We must mount an expedition at once
and we must take the Ogron as evidence.
我们必须立即安排一支队伍, 而且必须带上食人魔作为证据
The empires are on the verge of war.
俩帝国正处于战争的边缘
A Draconian spaceship in Earth space
一艘龙帝国飞船进入地球空间，
could be destroyed before it reaches its destination.
还没到达目的地就可能被摧毁了
We could use the ship the Master brought us in.
我们可以用法师带我们来的那艘飞船
It's an Earth police spaceship.
那是一艘地球警局的飞船
Females are not permitted to speak...
女人不允许说话...
The female may speak.
这个女人可以说话
But...
但是...
We must respect the customs of our guests, strange though they may be.
我们必须尊重我们客人的习俗，不管它们看起来多么奇怪
The suggestion had merit.
这项建议值得采纳
Thank you, Your Majesty.
谢谢你，陛下
You too, will go on this mission.
你，也将参加这次任务
But it must be headed by a Draconian of noble rank.
但必须得有龙族爵位的人带队
I shall send my son.
我将送我的儿子去
Doctor, where are we?
博士，我们在哪儿？
We're just about to cross the frontier into Earth space.
我们就要跨越边界进入地球空间了
Ooh, that's good.
喔，太好了
Unless your Earth people destroy us.
咱们可别被你们地球人摧毁了
Well, this is an Earth police spaceship, you know, sir.
这可是一艘地球警局的飞船，你知道吧
Even if it is stolen.
即使它是偷来的
What is that?
那是什么？
DOCTOR: It looks like another spaceship.
看起来像是又一艘飞船
It appears to be following us.
它好像一直跟着我们
OGRON: Look!
看！
MASTER: Well, that must be them.
好了，那肯定是他们
DOCTOR: We should be picking them up
on the visual scanner now.
我们现在应该能在视频扫描仪上看到他们了
JO: It's an Ogron ship!
这是艘 Ogron 的船
Fire!
开火！
DOCTOR: Hang on. I think we're shaking them off.
把住。我想我们我们可以甩掉他们
(OGRON GRUNTING)
Doctor!
博士！
He's broken out! Get out, Jo!
他逃出来了。出去，Jo！
MASTER: We must have hit them.
They're losing speed.
我们肯定击中他们了，他们速度下来了
OGRON: Shall I fire again?
要我再次开火吗？
No, no, it might be possible
to take the Doctor alive after all.
不不，必须要能够生擒住博士
Muster a boarding party.
召集一个登机小队
Yes, Master.
好的，法师
(OGRON GRUNTING)
Right, there you are, my friend.
好了，乖乖的吧，朋友
Are you all right?
你没事吧
JO: Oh, no, you don't!
噢，不，你不能！
No, no!
不，不！
- No, let go of me!
- This way!
- 不，放开我！  - 这边！
JO: Let me go!
放开我！
We've been boarded! We need the blasters, come on!
有人登船了！我们需要枪，快来！
- The prisoner?
- Don't worry about him.
- 俘虏呢？  - 不用操心他了
He's no use to us at the moment.
现在这个时候他对我们没用了
JO: Let me go! No! Doctor!
放开我！不！博士！
DOCTOR: Get down!
OGRON: The enemy!
- 蹲下！ - 有敌人！
OGRON: Fool, go!
傻瓜，走！
JO: Help! Doctor!
OGRON: You come!
- 救命，博士！  - 你过来！
- You must come!
- No!
- 你必须过来！  - 不！
Look out! We must take the girl!
小心！我们必须带着这个女孩儿！
No!
不！
In here!
进来！
MASTER: Right. Unlock!
行了。断开！
CAPTAIN ON RADIO:
This is Earth battle cruiser X29.
这里是地球战斗巡航舰X29
Do you read me? Identify yourself.
你能听到吗？请表明你的身份
This is Earth battle cruiser X29.
这里是地球战斗巡航舰X29
Do you read me? Identify yourself.
你能听到吗？请表明你的身份
Hello, this is Earth police spaceship 2390,
你好，这是地球警用飞船2390
on a special mission to the President of Earth. Over.
正在执行一项特殊任务，飞往地球总统。结束
CAPTAIN: Identify the ship
that has just unlocked from you.
表明刚与你船断开的飞船身份
They refuse to answer our signals.
他们拒绝应答我们的问话
Look, it's of vital importance
注意，这是非常重要的：
that you pursue and capture
that ship immediately. Over.
你们应该立刻追上那艘飞船，抓获他们。结束
You are in possession
of a stolen police spaceship.
你们占有了一艘被偷走的警用飞船
You are under arrest.
Stand by to be boarded.
你们被捕了。我们即将登船，请准备
DOCTOR ON RADIO:
Look, you don't understand.
听着，你没有弄明白
The man who stole this ship
is escaping in that vessel.
偷了这艘船的人正在用那个船上逃走
CAPTAIN: You are under arrest.
你们被捕了
You'll be given the opportunity
of making a full statement.
你们有机会做完整的陈述
Do not offer any resistance.
Stand by to be boarded.
不要做任何抵抗，我们即将登船
DOCTOR: Oh, very well.
We're standing by.
哦，好吧，我们待命
(LAUGHING)
Poor Doctor. Enmeshed in the throes of bureaucracy.
可怜的博士，陷入官僚主义的痛苦之中
(LAUGHING)
It'll take him a long time
to talk himself out of that one.
可得要些时间他才能说明白，再脱开身
But he'll get to see the President,
eventually.
但他最终会去见到总统
She won't believe him.
总统不会相信他
Oh, yes, she will, when she sees the Ogron prisoner.
哦，会，她会的，只要看见 Ogron 俘虏就会了
He's our evidence.
他是我们的证据
Your evidence is standing
right behind you.
你的证据正站在你的后面呢
The Draconian Prince knows
the truth and he's with the Doctor.
龙族王子知道真相，他也跟博士在一起
My dear, Miss Grant, in the climate
of opinion that I have created,
我亲爱的 Grant 小姐，在我制造的舆论趋势下
do you think that any Earthman
你觉得任何地球人
is going to believe the word of a Draconian?
会相信一个龙族人的话么？
Your Highness, we've heard the Doctor's theory before.
殿下，我们之前已经听过这个博士的理论
And, with respect, there is still no concrete evidence.
而且，恕我直言，它并没有可靠证据支撑
I myself would like to believe you
but, as you can see,
我个人倒是想要相信你。但是，如你所见
I need proof to convince my people.
我需要证据去说服我的人
Then we must mount an expedition
to the planet of the Ogrons.
那我们必须安排一队人去 Ogrons 的星球
The proof we need is there, madam.
我们需要的证据在那里，夫人
With Earth on the brink of war,
how can we divert our forces
眼看地球处于战争边缘，我们怎么能转移我们的力量
into such a pointless expedition?
去搞这种无意义的远征呢？
My dear chap, I'm not asking for a battle fleet.
我亲爱的伙计，我不是要求派一支战斗舰队去
All I require is one small spaceship.
我所要的只是一艘小飞船
Well, Miss Grant, welcome to my humble abode.
好了，Grant 小姐，欢迎来到我简陋的土屋
I think you were better off in prison.
我觉得你在监狱里过得比这更好
Oh, temporary quarters, my dear.
噢，临时住所而已，亲爱的
I shall soon be changing them
for something better.
我很快就会将他们换成更好的
Oh, you'll soon be back in jail.
噢，对，你很快就会回到监狱了
When the truth gets out,
等真相一出来
Earth and Draconia will combine
their forces to attack you.
地球和龙族就会联合起来对付你
I don't think so. There's too much distrust between them.
我不觉得。他们之间有太多的不信任
The Doctor will find you, eventually.
博士最终会找到你
Ah, there I agree with you. He must find me.
啊，这我倒是同意你的说法，他必须找到我
Not only to rescue you,
不仅是要来救你
but also to be reunited with his beloved TARDIS.
还要跟他所爱的 TARDIS 会合
Your Royal Highness, could you convince your people
殿下，你能否让你的人民相信
they were not being attacked by Earthmen?
他们并不是被地球人攻击的
(SIGHING) If only we had proof.
除非我们有证据
Then I could convince my people
and you could convince yours.
那样我就可以说服我的人民，你也能说服你的
But there's not much time.
但我们没有太多时间
Madam President, everything is ready.
We shall use my personal scoutship.
总统夫人，一切准备就绪了。我们用我个人的侦察舰
We'd better leave at once. Madam President.
我们最好马上离开，总统夫人
- My life at your command.
- Madam President.
- 听候您的差遣  - 总统夫人
DOCTOR: Right, 34 seconds,
找到了，34 秒
a course correction to galactic
coordinates 2349-6784.
航线调整为星际坐标 2349-6784
You realise where that will take us?
你知道那会带我们去哪儿吗？
A completely uninhabited sector
of the galaxy.
这个星系中一片完全无人居住的区域
Well, not completely uninhabited,
General Williams.
嗯，也不是完全无人居住，威廉将军
That's where the Ogron's planet is.
Orgons 的星球就在那里
No doubt your information is better than mine.
当然，你的信息比我全
- May I ask where you obtained it?
- Certainly. From the Master.
- 我能问问从哪儿知道的吗？ - 没问题。从法师那里
He fed the co-ordinates into his
ship's computer when I was his prisoner.
他之前把坐标输入到飞船电脑里面了，那会儿我还是他的俘虏
And after you'd captured the ship, sir,
在你捕获这艘飞船之后
I extracted the information
from the ship's memory banks.
我把这信息从飞船的记忆库中提取出来了
We're simply wasting time...
我们纯粹是在浪费时间...
Dragons!
龙族人！
Let me talk to them, I shall explain!
让我来跟他们说，我可以解释
Somehow I don't think they're in the mood
我怎么觉得他们这会儿没这个心情
for explanations at this minute.
根本不给我们解释的机会
- Can you outrun them?
- This ship can outrun anything.
- 你能跑得过他们吗？ - 这艘船跑得过任何船
Hyper-drive. Max hyper-drive!
超驱模式，开到最大！
- Right, we're out of range now.
- Reduce speed, return to course.
- 好了，现在够不着我们了  - 减速，回归原航线
MASTER: They should be here very soon now.
他们应该很快就到了
(DEVICE BEEPING)
Judging by the size of the ship, they can't be in any great force.
从飞船的大小来看, 他们的力量不可能太强
So conceal yourselves and ambush them
as soon as they arrive, right?
所以你们隐藏起来, 他们一到达就伏击他们，行吧？
Hold on, wait a minute.
Something's happened.
停，等一下。有点情况
They must have landed very nearby.
他们肯定已经在很近的地方着陆了
Right, send out patrols!
好，派出巡逻队
Get them and bring them
back here immediately.
抓住他们，立刻带回这里
And, remember, I want the Doctor alive.
并且记着，博士我要活的
OGRONS: Yes, Master.
是，法师
One dominant life form,
a large and savage reptile.
一种处于统治地位的生命形式，体型巨大，行为野蛮的爬行动物
Yes, well, let's hope
we don't encounter one.
好吧，期望我们一个也不要碰到
Doctor, has it occurred to you
what we're going to do
博士，你有没有想过我们该做什么...
when we discover the source of this signal?
...等我们找到这个信号的源头的时候？
I've no idea, old chap.
We'll find out when we get there.
我也没概念，老伙计，我们到了那儿应该就能发现了
Come on, can't be far.
快来，应该不远了
- Drop! Surrender!
- WILLIAMS: Take cover!
- 放下武器！投降！  - 隐蔽！
(GROWLING)
What is that?
那是什么？
I've no idea, but whatever it is,
it's on our side.
我也不知道，但不管是什么，它在帮我们
Yes, I await your arrival with the greatest of pleasure.
是的，我怀着极大的喜悦等待着你们的到来
And I shall be there to meet you
the moment that your ship touches down.
你们的飞船一沾地，我就在那里迎接你们
(OGRONS GRUNTING)
- So, where's the Doctor?
- The monster came.
- 怎么，博士在哪儿？  - 怪兽出来了
The monster?
And I suppose you all ran like rabbits?
怪兽？然后你们就跟兔子一样乱跑了？
- We fear the monster!
- You stupid, cowardly idiots!
- 我们害怕怪兽！ - 你们这群愚蠢、胆怯的笨蛋！
You will answer to your masters for this.
你们自己答复你们的主人吧
- What? They are coming?
- Yes, they are coming!
- 什么，他们到了？  - 是的，到了
Which means that I can dispense
with your doubtful assistance.
也就是我可以不要你们帮倒忙了
Out of my way!
给我闪开！
Hello, Doctor!
你好，博士！
So here you are at last, eh?
看来你终于到了，哈？
- Surrender or you'll be shot down!
- No, he's unarmed.
- 投降，要不然把你打下来！ - 不，他没武器
Unarmed maybe, but not unaccompanied.
可能是没武器，但并不算没帮手
I've brought some old friends along
to meet you.
我带来了一些老朋友跟你见见面
(MASTER LAUGHING)
Quite a touching little reunion.
多么令人感动的小重逢啊
(MASTER LAUGHING)
CHIEF DALEK: Doctor, you are in our
power and you will be exterminated.
博士，你在我们掌控之中了，你会被终结
- No, not yet.
-You will obey the Daleks!
- 不，还不要  - 你要服从 Daleks!
You know as well as I do
that this man does not fear death.
你们跟我一样清楚，这个人并不怕死
I want him to suffer a much worse punishment.
我希望他受到更严重的惩罚
Look, my skill and cunning
has brought about this war
听着，我靠我的技巧和狡猾挑起了这场战争
which will make you the masters of the galaxy.
而这场战争可以让你们成为这个星系的主人
Leave the Doctor with me
and let him see the result of that war.
把博士留给我，让他看看这场战争的结局
Let him see the galaxy in ruins.
让他看着这个星系变成废墟
Let him see the planet Earth,
that he loves so much, in ruins,
让他看着他深爱的地球变成废墟
then exterminate him.
然后再终结他
Very well. He will remain your prisoner
until the war is concluded.
好。他仍然是你的俘虏，直到战争结束
Then you will bring him to us
and we shall exterminate him.
然后你带他过来，我们会终结他
We shall now return to our base
and prepare the army of the Daleks.
我们现在返回我们的基地，准备 Daleks 军队
Oh, I suppose I should thank you
for saving my life?
噢，我觉得我应该感谢你救了我一命？
Not for long, Doctor.
It's going to be a very short war.
不会太久的，博士，这将是一场很短暂的战争
Right, take them away.
好了，把他们带走
- Hello, Doctor.
- Hello, Jo.
- 你好，博士  - 你好，Jo
Oh, so now they've got all of us.
噢，这样一来他们把我们所有人都抓了
All except the pilot. He's repairing the ship.
驾驶员还没，他在维修飞船
Why do these Dalek creatures wish
to set your people and mine at war?
为什么这些叫 Dalek 的东西期望你们和我们之间发生战争？
'Cause war will mean the extermination
of both empires, Your Royal Highness,
因为战争就意味着两个帝国的终结，殿下
and the Daleks will emerge
as the supreme rulers.
然后 Daleks 就会成为最高统治者
Now somehow, we've got to get
out of here and stop them.
现在，我们得想个什么方法逃出这里，然后阻止他们
(WHISPERING) Doctor! Doctor,
would the Master's little fear-box help?
博士！博士，法师的这个恐惧小盒子有用吗？
Well done, Jo!
干得好，Jo！
You see, we could use it
to frighten the Ogrons away
你们看，我们可以用它把那些 Ogrons 吓跑
and then we can all escape.
然后我就都可以逃走了
Well, that's hardly practical, Miss Grant.
这，不太好操作，Grant 小姐
They'd just run off and we'd still be locked in.
即使他们跑掉，我们还是关在里面
(SIGHING) Oh!
噢！
There is one thing we can do, though,
and it'll need a very slight adjustment.
不过，还有一个方法我们可以用，只需要做一点很小的调整
There's nothing to worry about.
没有什么可担心的
The Doctor will be perfectly safe
in my hands.
博士在我手中会很安全
And I promise you,
when I deliver him to you,
而我向你保证，当我把他交给你们的时候
he'll be a broken man.
他将是个废人
CHIEF DALEK OVER RADIO:
Do not fail the Daleks.
不要让 Daleks 失望
The war is certain now.
现在这仗是肯定要打了
And once the great empires
have destroyed each other,
一旦这两大帝国摧毁了对方
I ask but one thing, let me rule
the planet Earth in your name.
我只要求一件事情：让我以你们的名义统治地球
General Williams,
if we do manage to get out of here,
威廉将军，如果我们设法逃了出去
and Jo and I manage to create a diversion,
而Jo 和 我设法把他们引开了
could you find your way back
to your spaceship?
你能找到回到自己飞船的路吗？
- Certainly.
- Good.
- 当然  - 很好
Right, that should do it.
好，这样应该可以了
Now I want you to take off immediately.
我要你们立刻起飞
Get the truth back
to your respective governments.
把真相带回给各自的政府
Yes.
好
Tell them that they must mount
a joint expedition
告诉他们必须建立一支联合的远征军
- and capture this base at once.
- I shall stay and help.
- 要立刻攻占这个基地
- 我留下来帮忙
No, we'll need you to convince
the Emperor, Your Royal Highness.
不，我们需要你去说服皇帝，殿下
What about you and Miss Grant,
how will you get away?
你和 Grant 小姐怎么办，你们怎么逃走？
Jo, I presume that the TARDIS
is still here?
Jo，我估计 TARDIS 仍然在这里？
- Yes, I know where it is.
- Well, don't worry about us.
- 是的，我知道它在哪儿  - 那，不用担心我们了
- Our spaceship is here.
- That's all very well, Doctor,
- 我们的飞船在这里  - 那就太好了，博士
but we still happen to be locked in.
不过目前我们还是被锁在这里面啊
Yes, well, would you mind blocking your ears
是。不过你们不介意捂一下耳朵吧
and covering your eyes just for a moment?
眼睛也要盖住一会儿
I do not understand.
我没搞懂
No, but I think you will in a moment.
Just do as I ask, would you?
过一会儿你就能懂了。按我说的做，好吗？
- You, too, Jo.
- Oh, no, it's all right.
- 你也是，Jo  - 噢，不用，没事的
- I can resist it.
- Can you?
- 我能抵抗住  - 能吗？
- Yes.
- Good.
- 是的  - 好
DOCTOR: Uh, how much longer are you
gonna keep us locked in here?
啊，你们还能把我们锁在这里多久？
Yes, I'm talking to you.
是的，跟你说话呢
(HYPNOTIC PULSE SOUNDING)
Open the gate. Open the gate.
把门打开，把门打开
Open the gate or I will exterminate you.
把门打开，否则我终结你
It worked.
生效了
DOCTOR: Right.
JO: Come on, then. Follow me.
- 好
- 快点，跟着我
CHIEF DALEK OVER RADIO:
Do not fail the Daleks.
不要让 Daleks 失望
(SCOFFING)
Right, we'll see who rules
the galaxy when this is over.
行，等这事完了，我们来看看谁是这个星系的统治者
(MOCKINGLY IMPERSONATING THE DALEKS)
"Do not fail the Daleks", indeed!
“不要让 Daleks 失望“，真事似的
You stupid, tin boxes!
你们这些愚蠢的铁桶
(OGRON GASPING)
Why aren't you guarding the prisoners?
你为什么不看守着俘虏？
- The Daleks sent me away.
- There are no Daleks!
- Dalek 把我派开了  - 现在没有 Daleks！
- The Daleks have all left the planet.
- The Dalek said to open the cell.
- 他们已经离开这个星球了  - 那个 Dalek 说让我打开牢房
Did he now? Fetch the others!
I want them here immediately.
他说了？把其他人找来，我要他们马上到这里来
- Doctor, look at this.
- DOCTOR: Well, that's fascinating.
- 博士，看看这个  - 嗯，很迷人
Is it some sort of idol?
I saw one of the Ogrons worshipping it.
会不会是某种偶像？我看见一个 Ogrons 在拜它
Yes, I'm not surprised.
We've seen the real thing, haven't we?
哦，我不会奇怪的。我们刚才见过这种生物，是吧
They're probably more frightened of him
than they are of the Daleks.
他们可能更害怕他, 更甚过害怕 Daleks
Right, come on. This way.
好了，快来，这边
Right, you can get out this way. Good luck.
来，你可以从这条路出去。好运
- And you, Miss Grant. Doctor.
- General Williams.
- 你也是，Grant 小姐，博士
- 威廉将军
WILLIAMS: Farewell.
JO: Good luck.
- 再见  - 祝你好运
DOCTOR: Your Royal Highness.
PRINCE: My life at your command.
- 殿下  - 听候您的差遣
The TARDIS is over there.
TARDIS 就在那边
Going somewhere, Doctor?
要去哪儿，博士？
You know, you really are incredibly
persistent, aren't you?
知道吗，你还真是阴魂不散啊，是吧？
- That is my property, I believe.
- Oh, yes, a most ingenious device.
- 那是我的东西，我想  - 是的，这个设备做得很精巧
I congratulate you.
我恭喜你
OGRONS: Oh! The monster!
哦，有怪兽！
(HYPNOTIC PULSE SOUNDING)
- Oh, Doctor, I thought you were dead.
- Help me.
- 噢，博士，我还以为你已经死了  - 帮我一下
Come on, yes. Careful.
加油，好，小心点
- Help me into the TARDIS, Jo.
- Okay.
- 扶我进 TARDIS 去，Jo  - 好
- All right, Jo.
- Careful.
- 好了，Jo  - 小心点
The first thing we've got to do
is get out of here.
我们要做的第一件事，就是离开这里
(WHOOSHING)
(BEEPING)
(BREATHING DEEPLY)
Doctor, what are you doing?
博士，你在做什么？
Telepathic circuits,
sending a message to the Time Lords.
心灵感应回路，给时间领主传递一个信息